Finding Aid for the John Allison Benjamin Papers Biomed.0001
UCLA Library Special Collections
- V. THE JOHN A. BENJAMIN COLLECTION OF MEDICAL HISTORY
  - V. B. CORRESPONDENCE WITH RARE BOOK DEALERS
    - Various dealers, provenance file, 1944-1991 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      Argosy Book Stores, 1945-1946; Boston Medical Library, 1944; Carnegie Book Shop, 1948; F.F. Feigl, 1945; I.K. Fletcher, 1945, 1946; E.P. Goldschmidt, 1968; Paul B. Hoeber, 1943; Hoosier Bookshop, 1960; Hower Bookshop, 1965; B.M. Israel, 1967; H.P. Kraus, 1943; Harry A. Levinson, 1964; McGraw-Hill, 1966; Minerva Booksellers, 1944-1946; Peabody, 1949; Preidel, 1966; L. Pritzker, 1946; B. Quaritch, n.d.; Rittenhouse, 1964-1967; Rosenthal, 1949; Sandbergs, 1955; Scientific Library Service, 1967; H. Sotheran, 1947-1948; Specialty Book Concern, 1944; Staack, 1949; Swann Auction Galleries, 1946; E. Trip, 1963; Trotting Hill Park, 1991; Univ. of Pennsylvania Press, 1967; Williams & Wilkins, 1944
    - Various dealers, correspondence, 1943-1988 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      Argosy Book Stores; Davis & Orioli; Webb Dordick; H. W. Edwards; B.M. Israël; Walter D. Lantz; Minerva Booksellers, 1944; Peabody Book Shop; W.D. Postell; Orro H. Ranschburg; A. Rosenthal; E. Rosenthal; Specialty Book Concern
    - Unidentified & problem provenances, 1942-1968 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      723 Rare book dealer catalogs [n.d.] some pages saved by JAB; photocopies of annotations in entire catalogs made by JAB; (most originals, and unannotated catalogs, were discarded by the processor)
- VI.PERSONAL MATERIALS
  - Curriculum vitae, 1942, 1970 1972, 1981 1985, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    1942: two-page handwritten c.v. at age 36; 1970: JAB had in readiness for a financial valuation of the surgery program of Strong Memorial Hospital, with correspondence; 1972: one-page c.v.; 1981: "Publications since 1976," plus teaching, meetings attended, and memberships; 1985: c.v. includes "Education & appointments," "Committees," "Societies," "Contributions to," "Research grants," "Publications," "Books"; "Publications [by JAB] related to the history of medicine" with handwritten date of 6/5/85; 1988: a partial list of publications focused on pediatric urologic surgery, by JAB, by Richard S. Hurwitz, and by Harry C. Miller, with the handwritten note "mailed to Frank Hinney, Jr." (see also Box 4-F12, and Box 7-F31 for National Cyclopaedia of American Biography entry)
  - Obituaries, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    newspaper clipping from Glendale News-Press, Dec. 29, 1992; program of the memorial service, Dec. 29, 1992; text of the minister's funeral eulogy
  - UCLA commencement program, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    eleventh commencement, June 20, 1930; JAB received Bachelor of Arts in Zoology degree with the first class to graduate from the Westwood campus; for the actual degree, see Box 11-F4 1
  - Certificates of academic degrees, 1930, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Bachelor of arts, UCLA, 1930; Doctor of medicine, The Johns Hopkins University, 1934
  - Personal correspondence, 1925-1987 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    overlaps in content with other correspondence, e.g., Box 1-F8
  - Correspondence with Charles E. Huggins (Nobel laureate), 1952-1986 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    includes a photo of Dr. Huggins and his wife, "just before Nobel Prize, Dec. 10, 1966"; reprint of one & preliminary draft of another JAB book review, both mentioning Huggins; 35mm slides of Huggins, a Huggins letter and a Huggins inscription
  - Correspondence with (Sir) F. Douglas Stephens, 1976-1986 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    for portrait of Dr. Stephens, 1986, see Box 8-F8
  - Scrapbook, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    miscellaneous items, including some correspondence, newspaper & magazine clippings, portraits 1
  - Half-tone medical illustrations, 1942, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    9 x 11", mounted: in a 1991 note from JAB to Katharine Donahue, JAB explains that Matt Jacobs, a student of Max Brödel, was the teacher & JAB the student of medical illustration when he painted this half-tone; another 6 x 5 1/2", mounted, also painted by JAB, 1943
  - National Cyclopedia of American Biography, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    3x5" photo of JAB and reprint of his entry; correspondence
  - California certification in continuing medical education for JAB, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    certification of required medical education activity, 1971-1974, from the California Medical Association
  - Professional memberships, 1947-1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    letters of acceptance by the Western New York & Ontario Urological Society and the American Board of Urology; letter of application to the Central Section of the American Urological Society 1
  - Professional membership certificates, 1935-1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    served as House Officer on the Urological Service, The Johns Hopkins Hospital, 1935; American Board of Urology board certification, 1948
  - Membership certificates, 1946,1953, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Medical Library Association, supporting member, March 1, 1946; The American Museum of Natural History, associate member, Dec. 1, 1953; Aesculapians, UCLA School of Medicine, 1980 (for Aesculapian tie tack, see Box 9-Item 1); "honorary citizen," Boys Town, Nebraska, 1945
  - Proposed honorary UCLA degrees for Bennet Allen & Elmer Belt, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    correspondence between JAB, Belt, B. Allen & Raymond Allen
  - Sunday church program, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    for Nov. 29, 1970, Brighton Presbyterian Church, East Ave., Rochester, NY
  - Correspondence with G. (Jaime) del Amo, 1931-1943 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    JAB held a fellowship from the del Amo Foundation, and his research with Drs. Allen & Krichesky was partially supported by this Foundation
  - Correspondence with Norman E. Peterson, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    holograph letter from Dr. Peterson thanking JAB for JAB's 80th birthday story in UCLA Librarian (see Box 6-F29); Peterson enclosed reprint of his "Management of operative prostatic hemorrhage," in Monographs in Urology, 5(3): 66-92, May/Jun 1984; letter to JAB with enclosure of letters Peterson wrote in 1970, nominating JAB for a Modern Medicine Award for Distinguished Achievement (which was not awarded)
  - Max Shaw Dunn, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    program for memorial service & newspaper obituary for Dr. Dunn; annotation by JAB: "did post-graduate work with Dr. Dunn, 1928-1930, on Amo awards"
  - Honors from the American Urological Association, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    awarded honorary membership in the organization, 1984; interviewed by Harry C. Miller, Jr. for one in a series of historical videotaped interviews (for the videocassette, see Box 8-F81); correspondence; one photograph from the 1985 Anaheim AUA convention, partially identified; photographs of John Benjamin (JAB's son), Dr. & Mrs. Charles Huggins, Dr. Curt Richter, Sir Douglas Stephens, Dr. Wyland Leadbetter, & Dr. & Mrs. Elmer Belt, which JAB felt might be added to the videotape
  - JAB's Johns Hopkins Medical School class of 1934, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Hopkins Medical News, 9(2):Summer 1985, with JAB's short entry for biographies of The Johns Hopkins School of Medicine class of 1934, on the occasion of the 50th anniversary of their graduation; includes photos of JAB in 1934 & 1984; correspondence, notes
  - "John A. Benjamin, motives of a collector", 1990 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    half-page article in IMMI, the Index of Medieval Medical Images in North America, by Ynez O'Neill, with cover letter; see also JAB's letter to KESD, 7/29/90, in Box 6-F21
  - Kaiser Permanente Urology Symposium, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    program, with JAB's portrait on cover; David A. Bloom gave the annual Benjamin Lecture 1
- VII. NON-PRINT MATERIALS
  - VII. A. PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Group portrait with JAB, [n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 7)
      14 x 11" group portrait of five men, including JAB
    - Pictures of JAB, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 12)
      see also Box 2-F13, Box 6-F29, Box 7-F31, Box 8-F9, & others
    - Identified portraits, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 13)
      nineteen various-sized photographs, some with negatives, of: Bennet M. Allen; Arthur Binzwasser; Petrus Camper; J.M.T. Finney, Dean Lewis & Harvey Cushing; Hieronymus Fracastorius; Dr. Gerota; Matt E. Jacobs; Laennec; Ulfland & Lois Leadbetter; Lichtenberg; Carolus Linneus; Marc Malpighi; Dr. Nitze; William Osler; Michele Troja; Vesalius; William H. Welch; Erastus B. Wolcott; Hugh H. Young; see also Box 8-F8, & others
    - Unidentified persons, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 14)
      six photographs, two negative; some group shots
    - Bladder voiding, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 15)
      seven 8 x 10" photos, cystofluoroscopy of two named patients [RESTRICTED]
    - Bladder voiding, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 16)
      seventeen 8 x 10" and two 5 x 7" photos, cystofluoroscopy, no names
    - Tissue histology, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 17)
      eight 5 x 7" photographs of tissue micrographs, rat & human, some patient names [RESTRICTED]
    - Tissue histology, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 18)
      seven 5 x 7" and seventeen 4 x 5" photographs, some with negatives, no identifications
    - X-rays & tissue histology, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 19)
      twenty photographs mounted into four plates, unidentified illustrations for publications
    - Photographs, X-rays, pyelograms, tissue histology, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 20)
      ninety-nine photographs with patient names [RESTRICTED]
    - X-rays, pyelograms, tissue histology, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 21)
      twenty-six photographs, patients with no identification
    - Schematic drawings, urogenital system, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 22)
      eleven photographs, four negatives, & two drawings, no identification of source
    - Animal kidneys, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 23)
      ten photographs, one negative, & four drawings of dog, cat, lion, kangaroo, chimpanzee, rhesus monkey, & rat kidneys
    - Operative technique, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 24)
      eighteen 4 x 5" photos, rabbit, prostate; cover memo from Boris Krichesky
    - Operative technique, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 25)
      nineteen 5 x 7" photographs of drawings of operative technique, human
    - Cinefluography, [n,d.] (Box 8, Folder 26)
      three 5 x 7" photographs; apparatus & named staff
    - Graphs, charts, and tables (Box 8, Folder 27)
      sixteen various-sized photographs, some with negatives, some mounted on cardboard; source is given for some
    - Instruments and apparatus (Box 8, Folder 28)
      fourteen photographs & one negative, no identification
    - Reproductions from printed sources, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 29)
      seventeen photographs, no identification
    - Miscellaneous photographs, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 30)
      fourteen photographs
    - Early texts on urinalysis, 1350, 1580 [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 31)
      four 5 x 7" and three 3 1/2 x 5" photos, most with negatives, of early texts & illustrations of diagnostic urinalysis
    - Reproductions from early printed or manuscript sources, 15th-18th cent (Box 8, Folder 32)
      forty-four photographs, four negatives & one drawing, some identified; includes some book title pages
    - Reproductions from printed sources published in the 19th cent sixteen photographs & seven negatives; sources are at least partially identified (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Reproductions from printed sources published in the 20th cent sixty-one photographs & eleven negatives; sources are at least partially identified (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Copies of printed text, articles & journal title pages 19th -20th cent eighteen photographs, some identified (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - "All-star operation," The Johns Hopkins Hospital, 1904 (Box 8, Folder 36)
      one 8 x 10" photograph of the surgical amphitheater with Dr. Harvey Cushing, et al. 1
    - Annual meetings, American Urological Association, 1940, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      12 x 20" group photos of the banquet at the 37th and 46th annual meetings, 1940 and 1951
    - "Hippocratic plane tree on island of Cos, 1934", 1959 (Box 8, Folder 37)
      8 x 10" photograph, inscribed from "A. Plato Schwartz to John Benjamin, 4/6/59"
  - VII. B. X-RAYS
    - Kidney stones, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 38)
      a series of x-rays of identified patients; each pair accompanied by technical notes; four pairs of exposures in each folder, size 3 x 4 cm. or 5 1/2 x 7 1/2 cm. [RESTRICTED]
    - Kidney stones, cont'd. [RESTRICTED], 1943 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Kidney stones, cont'd. [RESTRICTED], 1943 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Kidney stones, cont'd. [RESTRICTED], 1943 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Kidney stones, cont'd. [RESTRICTED], 1943 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - X-rays of chimpanzee kidney, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 43)
      4 x-rays; original envelope bore inscription: "injected 7/22/46; kidney - chimpanzee; Dr. Wilbur Smith; inject diodrast (i.v.) usual strength"
    - Human hand and foot (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Unidentified x-rays, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - VII. C. MOTION PICTURES
    - "Suprapubic prostatectomy in the rabbit and intra-ocular transplantation of prostatic tissue" (Box 9, Reel Film 1)
      16 mm. black & white film on 7" reel; ca. 400' of film; original can had title written on label headed "Elmer Belt Urologic Group, 1893 Wilshire Blvd., Los Angeles, Calif."; film was mailed to JAB at Strong Memorial Hospital, Rochester, date unreadable
    - X-ray movies, urethral diverticulum, female, [n.d.] (Box 9, Reel Film 2)
      16 mm. black & white film on 7" reel; ca. 150' of film; original can mailed to JAB from Strong Memorial Hospital, Rochester, in Nov. 1972; handwritten slip attached says: "print on 3601; 2999; 3804; 5971 for Dr. Benjamin"; the name of each patient was added in JAB's handwriting [RESTRICTED]
    - "Portal - Vesalius", [n.d.] (Box 9, Reel Film 3)
      35 mm. microfilm on 3 1/2" reel, made by New York Academy of Medicine; caption written on original can; content: Preface, table of content, & chapters 1-16 of Histoire de l'Anatomie et de la Chirurgie, by Antoine Portal. Paris: P.Fr. Didot, 1770-1773. 6 vols. in 7
    - "#2644", [n.d.] (Box 9, Reel Film 4)
      16 mm. black & white film on 3 1/2" reel; ca. 25' of film; cinefluoro- gram?
    - "Observations on ureteral obstruction and contractility in man & dog" (Box 9, Reel Film 5)
      16 mm. color film with magnetic sound, 24 frames/sec, on 10 1/2" reel; ca. 600' of film; University of Rochester School of Medicine & Dentistry
    - "The use of x-ray cinematography in urological studies", 1959? (Box 9, Reel Film 6)
      16 mm. black & white film on 7" reel; ca. 350' of film; Univ. of Rochester School of Medicine & Dentistry; original can said "Cine mtg., 1959
    - "Cine studies of selected cases", 1966? (Box 9, Reel Film 7)
      16 mm. black & white film on 7" reel; ca. 350' of film; by Drs. Elliot O. Lipchik, JAB, James S. Watson, Jr., George H. Drake, and Mr. Sydney A. Weinberg, University of Rochester School of Medicine & Dentistry
    - "Cine studies of selected cases", [n.d.] (Box 9, Reel Film 8)
      exact same titles as on Film 7; this one on 10 1/2" reel; ca. 500' of film
    - "Cine observations on the ureter in man and dog", 1969 (Box 9, Reel Film 9)
      16 mm. black & white film on 7" reel; ca. 110' of film; by Drs. JAB, Elliot O. Lipchik & James S. Watson, Univ. of Rochester School of Medicine & Dentistry
    - "Ureteral reflux", 1971 (Box 9, Reel Film 10)
      16 mm. black & white film on 7" reel; ca. 400' of film; Univ. of Rochester School of Medicine & Dentistry
    - "First x-ray cinematograph film ever taken, shown by Dr. Macintyre at the London Royal Society, 1897", 1973 (Box 9, Reel Film 11)
      16 mm. black & white film on 3 1/2" reel; sent to JAB by Dr. John Scott of Glasgow, co-worker of Dr. Macintyre
  - VII. D. FILMSTRIPS
    - Guglielmo, da Saliceto. Summa conservationis et curationis, Piacenza, 1476 (Box 9, Reel FS 1)
      35 mm microfilm from the Army Medical Library, ordered 1945; three pages of Chapter 140; also on the film: G. Fallopius. Observationes anatomicæ, Venice, 1561, 8 pages dealing with the kidney
    - Zerbis, Gabriele de, Liber anathomie corporis humani..., Venice, 1502 (Box 9, Reel FS 2)
      35 mm microfilm from the Army Medical Library, ordered 1946; parts concerning Zerbis' sieve theory of kidney function, leaves 33-37, 47-50, plus index
    - Fallopius, G. Observationes anatomicæ, Paris & also Venice, 1562 (Box 9, Reel FS 3)
      35 mm microfilm from the Army Medical Library, ordered 1945; the pages on the kidney, filmed from both the Paris & the Venice editions of 1562
    - Schellhammer, G.C. Phocae maris anatome..., 1699 (Box 9, Reel FS 4)
      35 mm microfilm from the Army Medical Library; "Appendix, annum VII & VIII, Decuriae III, Ephemeridum medico-physicarum Academiæ Cæsareo Leopoldinæ"
    - Cheselden, William, The Anatomy of the Human Body, London: Bowyer, 1730 (Box 9, Reel FS 5)
      35 mm microfilm from the Army Medical Library, ordered 1943; Appendix. Chapter 1. "A short historical account of cutting for the stone, pp. 339-355
    - Monro, Alexander. The History and Progress of Anatomy. Edinburgh, 1742 (Box 9, Reel FS 6)
      35 mm microfilm from the Army Medical Library, ordered 1946; holograph title page and pp. 60-63, collected from the lectures of Alexander Monro
    - Gruber, [?] article on prostate, title not given, 1847 (Box 9, Reel FS 7)
      35 mm microfilm from the Army Medical Library, ordered 1942; from Archiv für Anatomie, Physiologie, und wissenschaftliche Medicin, ?(6):469-476, 1847
    - Launois, P.E. "De l'atrophie de la prostate", 1894 (Box 9, Reel FS 8)
      35 mm microfilm from the Army Medical Library, ordered 1942; from Annales des maladies des organes génito-urinaires, 12(10):721-759, 1894
    - Roth, M. "Die Anatomie des Leonardo da Vinci", 1907 (Box 9, Reel FS 9)
      35 mm microfilm from the Army Medical Library, ordered Oct. 1944; from Archiv für Anatomie und Entwicklungsgeschichte, Suppl. 1907, pp. 1-122
    - Cineurography, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 46)
      five 15 mm film strips, 1 to 6 " long, of bladder
  - VII. E. 35 mm SLIDES
    - Slide page 1 (from carousel), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 47)
      20 slides: Morgagni's De Sedibus (Venice, 1761) & ureteral reflux; Dr. & Mrs. Belt; two slides of Jake Zeitlin; Dr. Charles O'Malley; tribute to O'Malley; Chancellor Murphy, Dr. & Mrs. Bennet Allen; Dr. Krichesky (?); Dr. & Mrs. Charles Huggins; letter & notes from Dr. Huggins; early Johns Hopkins surgical team; note from Dr. Hugh H. Young; Benjamin Collection book plate; unidentified manuscript pages; title page, Anatomia Mundini..., by Johann Dryander; unidentified anatomical illustrations; title page of Berengario da Carpi's Isagogae breves...
    - Slide page 2 (from carousel ), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 48)
      20 slides: paragraph of text (on the kidney?); composite diagram of probable anatomical finding of Berengario da Carpi; diagram of kidney development, 5-7 weeks; arterial tree of horseshoe kidney in newborn; variations in horseshoe kidneys; horseshoe kidney in rat; title page of Vesalius' De humani corporis fabrica, Basel, 1543; Vesalius quote; several Vesalius kidney illustrations; simplified kidney diagram; title page of Lorenzo Bellini's Exercitatio anatomica..., Florence, 1662; several kidney illustrations; title page of Bartolome Eustachi's Opuscule anatomica... Venice, 1564; kidney illustrations; title page of William Bullein's Bulwarke of defence againste..., London, 1579; quote from Bullein; woodcuts of Saint Cosmus & Saint Damius
    - Slide page 3 (from carousel), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 49)
      20 slides: laboratory, x-ray movie table (?); ultrasonic tranducer in semielipsoid; two slides of patient with concretion of urine; page from table-of-contents & one of text from Aulus Cornelius Celsus' De medicina...; title page of William Osler's The Principles and Practice of Medicine, 1892; quotes from Hippocrates & Plato; title page of Darwin's On the Origin of Species, 1859; a quote (from Darwin?); title page of Copernicus' De revolutionibus orbium celestium, 1543; title page of Galileo's Dialogo..., 1632; title page of Newton's Philosophiae naturalis principia mathematica, 1687; two pages of text & diagrams from Newton; Abraham Flexner's Medical Education in the United States and Canada, 1925; title page of William Harvey's Exercitatio anatomica de motu cordis..., 1628; two illustrations from Harvey; quote from Vesalius about Rhazes' Paraphrasis
    - Slide page 4 (from carousel and various boxes) (Box 8, Folder 50)
      20 slides: title page of Vesalius' Paraphrasis..., 1537; page of text (Latin; from Vesalius?); diagram - precursor of Lichtleiter (?); bust & 3/4 portraits of Dr. Allen; end-of-lecture slide saying "Thank you"; portrait of Curt Richter; signature of Curt Richter; title pages of reprints of two articles by Richter & JAB; bibliographic entry of JAB's 1935 article in Anatomical Record; introductory slide for lecture (?) "Books and Men: the Growth of Knowledge"; page of text (Latin); two slides of illustrations from old texts; portrait of Hugh J. Jewett; three illustrations; illustration of the Lichtleiter; schematic drawing, possibly Lichtleiter precursor (?);Fig. 12.8 from unidentified publication: embryonic development of G.U. system; Fig. 3 from JAB's "Observations on fused kidneys..."
    - Slide page 5 (from carousel), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 51)
      20 slides: "Willard E. Goodwin: Contributions to the history of urology..."; portrait of Goodwin on program for tribute to him, 1986; slide saying "Willard E. Goodwin, M.D., and history of urology; slide saying "Thank you, William E. Goodwin, M.D."; snapshot of W.E. Goodwin at Mt. Everest base camp; beginning of an article by Goodwin on Alexander von Lichtenberg; beginning of a memoir by Elmer Belt on von Lichtenberg; portrait of von Lichtenberg; Drs. Goodwin & Belt; two slides of Drs. Longmire, Goodwin, Belt, 1978; group of three men in parking lot, one of whom is Dr. Longmire; Governor Earl Warren signing bill creating UCLA School of Medicine, Dr. Belt in group; portrait of William H. Welch; portrait of Johns Hopkins; Johns Hopkins Hospital in 1889; interior of John Shaw Billings administrative building; cartoon, JAB & Goodwin (?), Hopkins dome in background, 1935; portrait of Hugh H. Young; portrait of Moses Swick
    - Slide page 6 (from carousel), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 52)
      20 slides: pen & ink portrait of Caspar Frederich Wolff; embryonic anatomy, drawings, from a printed book; photomicrograph; drawings, embryonic genito-urinary system; beginning of an article by Emil A. Tanagho et al., J. Urol. 93, 1965; drawing of trigone of the bladder (?); drawings of muscles during bladder activity; Figs. 17, 18, & 19 from JAB's "Urological x-ray cinematography"; Fig. 3 from JAB's "Infection & vesicoureteral reflux..."; Figs. 1, 4, 7, 6 from Curtis J. Lund's "Cinefluorographic studies...I."; Fig. 10 from unidentified publication: surgical methodology in prostate operation; Fig. 2 from unidentified publication: operation on vesical orifice in female; Fig. 1, from Gertrude Falk's "Observations on water diuresis...," and graphs 3, 2, & 1
    - Slide page 7 (from carousel), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 53)
      20 slides: Fig. 4 from JAB's "Cineradiographic observations of ureteral functions in man & dog"; Figs. 20, 21, 22, 23, 25, 26, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 16A, B & C, & cover from JAB's "Urological x-ray cinematography"; a quotation; drawings from a publication, of submucosal ureter; title: "Vesico- ureteral reflux produced experimentally in the female dog"; "Epilogue"; "Society for Pediatric Urology...1963. Guest speaker...F. Douglas Stephens..."; "Douglas Stephens Symposium...1986..." - two quotes; two drawings for "Vesico-ureteral reflux...female dog"; sketches of mesonephric duct malformations by F. Douglas Stephens, inscribed by Stephens; copy of same sketch, with inscription: "John, is this the sort of thing you need"